Alpish Jain

18th main, Indiranagar, Bangalore, Karnataka 560008

Profile Summary

Software Engineer with 3+ years of experience in full-stack development, REST API integrations, building scalable systems, and writing clean, maintainable code that drives real impact. Highly motivated, a quick learner, and always eager to take ownership and grow within high-performing teams.

Education

University of Petroleum and Energy Studies

June 2018 - July 2022

Bachelor of Technology, Computer Science and Engineering - CGPA: 8.4/10

Dehradun, Uttarakhand

Experience

Salesforce

June 2022 – Present

Associate Technical Consultant

Bengaluru, Karnataka

- Automated Loan Processing by implementing synchronous RESTful integration with FinnOne system, scaled to handle 10000+ applications daily, fulfilling complex compliance requirements of the bank making loan approvals faster by 50% and error-free for end users.
- Built front-end UI for streamlined telephonic verification of loan applicant, resulting in a 70% reduction in manual input time for the Underwriting team.
- Automated fraud detection logic using asynchronous RAMP API integration with Salesforce along with a front-end
 UI built using LWC to display the results, resulting in reduction of manual verification time by 90% for income
 assessment team.

Salesforce Jan 2022 – June 2022

Associate Technical Consultant Intern

Dehradun, Uttarakhand

- Architected the **data model**, implemented complex business logic, and delivered a **live demo** to senior developers for the capstone project, receiving **excellent feedback**.
- Developed scalable asynchronous Apex logic to send scheduled notifications to 10,000+ users across 600+ global locations when defined SLAs were breached, based on the escalation matrix.
- Completed code reviews, utilised best practices, and followed Agile workflows. Wrote and optimized Apex logic with 100% test coverage.

Highpolar Softwares

June 2021 - August 2021

Front End Developer Intern

Dehradun, Uttarakhand

- Developed the front-end of a cross-platform Instant Messaging app for iOS and Android using React Native.
- Integrated with Google Firebase for real-time messaging and collaborated on REST API integration with a Django backend and utilised Git as a tool for version control.
- Crafted scalable, extensible code following MVC architecture, SOLID and DRY principles, and ensured quality through Smoke, Unit, and End-to-End (E2E) testing.

Projects

Majestic Hotels | Java, React.js, MySQL

November 2024

- Built a full-stack hotel booking management app with **React.js frontend**, **Spring Boot backend** with 20+ RESTful APIs for **room search**, **booking**, and **user management**.
- Implemented user authentication/authorization and role based access for admins and customers using JWT.
- Integrated MySQL for storing Rooms data, user accounts, and bookings. Also, utilized Amazon S3 for storing high resolution images for 100+ rooms and implemented pagination for efficient data retrieval.

Technical Skills

Languages: Python, Java, C, HTML/CSS, JavaScript, SQL, C++, Apex

Developer Tools: VS Code, Git, GitHub, Heroku, Jira, Postman, Redis, Eclipse, Android Studio, Intellij IDEA, Jupyter Notebook, Firebase, MySQL, MongoDB, Apache Kafka

Technologies/Frameworks: Spring Boot, React.js, LWC, Redux toolkit

Certifications / Extracurricular

- * Semi-finalist of Times of India quiz challenge.
- * Received the **Achiever of the month** award among **3000**+ employees for November FY'25 for outstanding performance and efforts.
- * Solved **400+ problems** on Leetcode.
- * Deep Learning Specialization, Coursera View Credentials